So this is our entreaty Tab View for both Android and iOS.
这是 Android 和 iOS 版的 EntryDetail 视图
Wouldn't it be cool if in the header up here,
如果在顶部的标题部分
we had the date for the specific day.
显示当天的日期 会不会酷一些？
In this case, August 8, 2017.
这里应该显示 2017 年 8 月 8 日
Well, good news.
好消息是
We can actually do that.
我们可以实现这一点
So the way we can do that is,
方法是...
you'll notice that with our StackNavigator and also with our TabsNavigator.
对于 StackNavigator 和 TabsNavigator
We passed an options as the second argument right here,
我们在这里以及在这里的 navigationOptions 下面
and then also right here under navigation options.
传入了选项作为第二个参数
Well if we want to dynamically set specific options,
如果我们想动态地设置特定的选项
we can do that in the component itself by adding a static property to it.
我们可以在组件本身里通过添加静态属性进行设置
So, we can come up here and say Static,
转到这里 输入 static
we will say navigation options. It's going to be a function.
然后输入 navigationOptions 它是一个函数
This function is going to be passed navigation.
向该函数中传入 navigation
So now what we can do is,
现在转到这里
we can come out here and say, entryID,
输入 entryId
which we are getting from this long property here that we're passing over.
来自于我们在这里传入的长长的属性
This is going to come from navigation.state.params.
设为 navigation.state.params
So again, where this is coming from is when we actually route to our EntryDetail view.
这段代码的原理是 当我们转到 EntryDetail 视图时
What we're doing is we're saying,
这段表示
go to EntryDetail and pass along this entryID,
转到 EntryDetail 并传递这个 entryId
which is just the key for the specific day.
也就是这一天的 key
So now what we can do is,
现在我们可以
we can return a title and whatever we put right
返回一个 title
here is now going to be the title inside this header.
在这里输入的任何内容将显示在这个标题上
So what we want to do instead is,
我们对日期
let's go ahead and format our date a little bit.
进行格式设置
So we'll say year is going to be entryId.slice from zero to four,
将 year 设为 entryId.slice(0, 4)
and then month is going to be that exact same thing but going from five to seven,
month 格式完全一样 但是从 5 到 7
and then day is going to be entryID.slice, everything after eight.
day 将为 entryId.slice(8)
So then, what we can do down here,
然后在这里
is using template strings,
使用模板字符串
we can say a month slash day slash year.
输入 $/$/$
And then now, when we go to a specific date for our entry detail view,
现在 当我们转到某一天的 EntryDetail 视图时
what we will see up here is the date itself.
将在这里看到日期本身
And one thing I didn't mention earlier,
我之前没提到的一点是
that I really like about ReactNavigation,
ReactNavigation 具有一个好处
is notice here the transition on Android is very Android-y.
这里的过渡效果非常 Android 化
There's that kind of pop up. And the transition on iOS is a whole different transition,
是一种弹出效果 而 iOS 上的过渡效果则完全不一样
because again, iOS is a very different platform than Android.
因为 iOS 平台与 Android 截然不同
It has a very different feel to it and the animations should reflect those feels.
它们具有不同的行为 动画效果也应该体现这种不同之处